<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrew Beers</title>
    <description>I work in CyberSecurity at Walmart and enjoy personal app development for iOS and Android
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 08:47:42 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 08:47:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Competing at CCDC Regionals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Competing at CCDC Regionals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our University of Arkansas team got a lot of experience competing at CCDC regionals. For a lot of the team members, this was there first time in a high-pressure environment dealing with real-world technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competition was two 10-hour days where the Walmart read team, a team of professional good-guy hackers, would try to break into our systems and we had to keep them out. There were no breaks, and the competition was designed to generate as much stress as possible in the short amount of time allotted. This was done by having misconfigured systems, people walking into the room to make other requests that had to be done quickly, and a CEO that would come and yell at use when things weren’t online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competition served as a great learning experience for everyone because they had to learn new technologies in an unfamiliar environment under a time constraint. We had people on our team that new each platform (Windows, Linux, Mac, Firewalls, and VMWare ESXi) and put their skills to use. I would recommend anyone interested in security to join a team and compete because it provides a great starting point for technologies and skills to learn in preparation of the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/10/ccdc-regionals-competiton.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/05/10/ccdc-regionals-competiton.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Qualifying for CCDC Regionals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our University of Arkansas CCDC team qualified for the SWCCDC regionals competiton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;587&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/ccdcregionals.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the second year our team competed in the CCDC (Collegiate Cyber Defense competition). Last year we had about half a team and no practice and got roasted. This year we have the opportunity to get compete again, but in Tulsa, OK at regionals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year’s CCDC qualifier was used as a learning opportunity. We had never competed before and nobody at our university had knowledge of the types of challenges we would face. During the competition, we took notes over the types of challenges, tools we would need in the future, how the team communicated, and useful roles to recruit for next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we built several labs to get everyone familiar with linux, networking, firewalls, VMWare ESXi (this was a big one), and common services like web and ftp servers. We divided our team into roles based on Linux, Windows, business injects, and one person to communicate between all of the teams. We also did a trial run, where we overloaded the team with injects and took notes over where everything broke down, and what people’s strengths and weaknesses were. Then we went to the whiteboard and came up with our roles, communication methods, steps to take when the competition starts, and how to pass tasks between teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would use the white board to keep track of which VMs people were working on to prevent any conflicts and properly assign new technical injects. For business injects, one person on the business inject team would take ownership of the inject and do the majority of the work, then pass it off to a second person for a final review before submitting it. If the business person needed details from a technical person, they would ask the team lead and they would get the information whenever the technical people had some free time. The team lead was also responsible for writing reports follow-up reports after any of the technical people found a breach in systems, or when systems went down and when we could get them back up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/13/ccdc-regionals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/03/13/ccdc-regionals.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shell On The Border</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weekends ago, I got to compete at the Shell on the Border cybersecurity event hosted by fs2600. Our team placed 7th out of 21 teams by solving a wide variety of questions. It was a great learning experience and really highlighted that there is room for every skill type in security, whether it’s cracking shells, social engineerings, or writing code to solve problems quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1128&quot; height=&quot;412&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/cyberhogs-lines.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1128&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/cyberhogs-circle.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/21/shell-on-the-border.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/02/21/shell-on-the-border.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lets Wrap - Cross Device App Practice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently updated the first app I built to, Let’s Wrap, to support iPhone X. It lets you calculate what size to cut wrapping paper for a present. I built this app in early 2016 because I wanted to work at Metova doing iOS development. I thought what better way to prove I can be an app developer than to publish an app! The biggest challenge with this app was supporting every device size. The iPhone X notch borked everything of course, I had to set custom constraints to handle the iPad vs iPhone, and extra code to handle how the app responds to the keyboard on iPad Pro 12.9 inch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, it also had a spike in US downloads on December 24th. Way to go guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1256&quot; height=&quot;277&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/letswrap.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/17/lets-wrap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/17/lets-wrap.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Razorback Transit Firebase Analytics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Razorback transit has been live for a couple months, and I’ve collected some anonymous data on how people use the app. There are 68 downloads on Android and 296 downloads on iOS, So nearly all downloads are active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;934&quot; height=&quot;530&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/razorbacktransit-useracount.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app opens to the live map by default, so if a user only uses the live map tab it won’t show up in the Tab Selected category. Parking is naturally least used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;465&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/razorbacktransit-tabs.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demographics that use Android and iOS are interesting as well. Android (left) is mostly male users (male is dark blue), with a wider age distribution. iOS (right) is more evenly distributed between gender but has a smaller age distribution. The gender and age data is handled by Google using the unique device ID that they have associated with your google account, which contains age and gender data. This is all the detail that is logged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;751&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/razorbacktransit-userdemographics.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, here’s the iOS device types of people using the app&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;488&quot; height=&quot;255&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/razorbacktransit-devicemodels.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/13/razorback-transit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/12/13/razorback-transit.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AR Startup Crawl App in Private Alpha</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After the startup crawl in 2017, I had a few ideas on how to improve the guest experience. I decided to make an app with the locations of startups, which beer is served where, descriptions of the companies, and a live update section so Startup Junkie can keep patrons up to date during the event. It’s just a side project, but it will be ready for 2018 and help bring Fayetteville further into the tech scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is powered Google Cloud Platform and Firebase for usage analytics, crash reporting, data storage, and push notifications. All data and styles in the app can be configured in real time post-deployment with Firebase Realtime Database, making it easy to do testing and quickly make changes based on what customers want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1400&quot; height=&quot;425&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/arstartupcrawl.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/11/arstartupcrawl-alpha.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/12/11/arstartupcrawl-alpha.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CompTIA Secuirty+ Certified</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just passed my CompTIA Security+ certification yesterday! It took a lot of reading and lynda.com videos, but it was worth it. It was a good foundation for vocabulary and common techniques used in cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1500&quot; height=&quot;1156&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/comptia.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/09/comptia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/09/comptia.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Razorback Transit App Now Live</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After listening to students about what they wanted out of Razorback Transit (our campus bus service), I built the razorback transit! The app intelligently caches all of the images for busses and stops to reduce network usage, decrease startup time, and stabilize performance in areas with low/spotty connectivity. Because of all of the caching, the bus locations can be updated every 5 seconds with minimal network usage (just a single JSON request). It is now live for both iPhone and Android with over 200 downloads between the two platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/razorbacktransit-release.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/09/razorbacktranist-release.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/08/09/razorbacktranist-release.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Arkansec 16 First Place Team</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, 10/21/16, a few of our U of A ACM members went to the ArkanSec16 hackathon to test our skills. We attended a 3 hour intro session about Kali Linux and various penetration testing tools. The competition was hosted using the open source Facebook CTF framework with custom questions and hacking challenges. Our team will be going back next year to see if we can keep it up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;302&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/arkansec.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/10/21/arkansec.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/10/21/arkansec.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Attended the NWA Tech Summit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to ACM, I had the opportunity to attend the 2016 NWA Tech summit. I got to hear from some great speakers and see what new technology is disrupting the industry (check out “Digimarc”, it’s awesome) as well as catch up with a few people from Walmart Security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;674&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/techsummit.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/10/10/tech-summit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/10/10/tech-summit.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
